Guide to the George Coffin papers, 1858-1896 MS2048
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Political Cartoons, 1891-1896, undated; MS2048 Series 1
  - Inter-State Commerce, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - (no title), undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - (no title), undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - (no title), undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - (no title), undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - The New Statue, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - A Coolness Between Them, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Why don't it Drop?, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Cock of the Week: The Democratic Rooster to the American Eagle and Thanksgiving, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Great National Quadrennial Game of Ninepins, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Little German Cemetery, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Day of Small Things, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The Colossus of Roads, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Thanksgiving Good Wishes 1885 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Ye Golden Summertide, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - That Giddy Old Widow Again, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - That Sherman Statue, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - (no title), undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - A Commendable Resolve, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - When Italy has Captured America, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - The Political Lazarus Begging fro the Crumbs from the Rich Man's Table, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - General Washington to General Greeley..., undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - The Political Debutante, 05/24/1891 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Mere Midsummer Madness, 07/19/1891 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The Point of View, 11/01/1891 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Columbia's Leap Year Valentine, 02/14/1892 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - After Service, 05/17/1892 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - The Post's Panorama of the Topics of the Week, 06/18/1893 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The Post's Panorama of the Topics of the Week, 07/09/1893 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Prodigal's Return, 11/30/1893 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - A Happy New Year 1894, 12/31/1893 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Lady or the Tiger? A Question Recently Solved, 11/11/1894 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Some Random Opinions of a Recent Disturbance, 11/15/1894 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Watchman! Tell us of the Night, 12/04/1894 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - A Fin d'Siecle Reconciliation Right off the Gridiron, 01/27/1895 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Masterpieces of Modern Art No. 2 The Vestal Tuccia, 02/03/1895 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Stabbed in the House (and Senate) of his ends, 02/15/1895 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Pollice Verso" After the Famous Picture by Gerome, 02/17/1895 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The Busy B's, 03/02/1895 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Procession of the Sacred Bull, 03/09/1895 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Proposed Group of Trilby Statuary for Portico of the Executive Mansion, 04/14/1895 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Perhaps Sorry He Spoke, 04/21/1895 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - The "Forecaster" That Runs the Bureau, 07/11/1895 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - And the Wind Blew Through Their Wiskers, 07/28/1895 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Harrison and Grace Before Meat, 10/02/1895-10/04/1895 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - The Balance of Power, 10/16/1895 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Halloween Ag Statesmen, 11/01/1895 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - A Scriptural Incident: The Prophet, the Ass, and the Angel - Numbers, XXII - 30, 11/10/1895 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Hansel and Gretel A la Mode, 11/24/1895 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - That Motherly Old Lady on the Dome, 12/01/1895 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Here It Comes, 12/03/1895 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - A Scoop on Santa Claus, 12/22/1895 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Our Good end - The Bear, 12/27/1895 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - (no title), undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - A Tied-Waiter of the Administration, 01/03/1896 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - After the Holidays, 01/04/1896 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Things Theatrical, 01/05/1896 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Almost Big Enough for Recognition, 01/10/1896 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - From "The Children's Book", 01/13/1896 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Four Wealthy Towns Contend For Homer Dead; Through which the Living Homer Begged His Bread, 01/15/1896 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - The South Carolina Cyclone, 01/31/1896 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Nero, 02/02/1896 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Down and Out, 02/05/1896 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Cleopatra Brought Before Caesar, 02/07/1896 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - The Perpetual Adoration of Grover, 02/08/1896 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Perhaps Mr. Bayard was Right, 02/09/1896 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Post No Bills, 02/16/1896 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Horatius At the Bridge, 02/20/1896 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - I Want Yer, Ma Honey! I do., 02/21/1896 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - As Dead as Julius Caesar, 02/27/1896 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Cadmus and the Dragon's Teeth, 03/01/1896 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - A Story Without Words, 03/09/1896 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Two Rival Side Shows, 03/14/1896 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Doing the Split, 03/20/1896 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Sulking In the Tents, 03/21/1896 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Warned Off. But Nevertheless and Notwithstanding., 03/25/1896 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - A Solitary Horseman, 03/26/1896 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - That Deadly Dope, 04/02/1896 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - 54th Congress. A Post Poster For Easter., 04/05/1896 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Egg-Rolling At the White House, 04/06/1896 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - A Long Lead, 04/09/1896 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - A Florida Enchantment, 04/10/1896 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - The Old Sexton, 04/17/1896 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Patience, 04/19/1896 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Whistling in the Dark, 04/25/1896 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - The Wailing Place of the Bosses, 05/09/1896 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Apropos of Statuary, 05/14/1896 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - The Prodigal's Return, 05/21/1896 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Hard Luck, 05/22/1896 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Nothing Left, 05/27/1896 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Too Much Silver Lining, 06/02/1896 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - The McKinley Flying Machine, 06/05/1896 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Getting on the Bandwagon, 06/14/1896 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Getting Together on the Platt-Form, 06/16/1896 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - The Standard Bearer, 06/19/1896 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - There's a Sweet Little Cherub That Sits Up Aloft to Look Out for the Life of Our Bill, 06/20/1896 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - In Blocks of Four, 06/25/1896 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - The Busy "Bs" that Buzz Beneath the Bonnet of Dame Democracy, 07/02/1896 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - As It was Written, 07/03/1896 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - The Modern Joshua, 07/16/1896 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - A Year of Splits, 07/22/1896 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Trilby Redivivus, 07/27/1896 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Come Now, Major, This Ostrich Business Won't Do, 07/30/1896 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Between Three Stools, 08/01/1896 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Proud as a Peacock with Two Tails, 08/05/1896 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - "And a Little Child Shall Lead Them", 08/06/1896 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - An Uneven Contest, 08/16/1896 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Pygmalion and Galatea, 08/18/1896 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - A Fog-Horn Conclusion, 08/20/1896 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Billy Wants a Gracker? Nit., 08/23/1896 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - W(e)ary William McKinley, 08/24/1896 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - By Balloon to the Pole, 08/30/1896 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Mr. Harrison- "I thought I heard a Noise", 09/02/1896 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - In East Capitol Park, 09/06/1896 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - The Knetpp Cure Up to Date, 09/07/1896 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Candidate Billy's Busy Day, 09/13/1896 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Some Casual Cartoonlets, 09/16/1896 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Distressing Predicament of the Hon. John Boyd Thacher, 09/26/1896 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - In the Hands of Their ends, 09/27/1896 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - The Passing of Li Hung Bryan, 09/28/1896 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Senator Hill Says He Would Rather See the Democratic Party - Well, Any way, That's What the Senator Says, 09/29/1896 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - The Crime of '96, 10/02/1896 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Overmatched, 10/04/1896 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - MacBeth and the Witches, 10/15/1896 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - What! Wheat?, 10/20/1896 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Lots of Fun, 10/23/1896 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - A Questionable Business, 10/24/1896 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - "The Philistines Be Upon Thee, Samson.", 10/29/1896 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - A Cabinet Officer's Nightmare, 11/02/1896 (Box 9, Folder 107)
- Civil War Illustrations, 1860s-1880s; MS2048 Series 2
  - Gertrude Amberger, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Arctic Storm, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bon Marche, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Buell, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Bull Run, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Captain Michael, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Chancellorsville, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Ego, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Eighth Page, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Exciting Adventures, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Fire Zouave, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - First Article, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Fuel Beans, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - The Guntown Trip, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - How I won My Wife, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Ill-Fated, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Lonesome Charley, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Lost Army, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Loyal Mountaineers, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - The Mysterious Message, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - The National Rifles, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Phantom Cavalry, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Prison Life, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Real Russia, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Release of Prisoners, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Sailor's Creek, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Salisbury, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - The Sanders Raid, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Shiloh, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Soldiering, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Stampeded Yanks, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - The Stay at Home Guards, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Story, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Sykes Regulars, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - A Western Battle, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Wilson's Road, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Between Two Fires, undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Boy Duke, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Boy Spy, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - C.C.C., undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Canned Peaches, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Capture of Blakely, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - The Cannoneer, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Chickamauga, undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Fort Harrison, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Gregg's Cavalry, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Island No. 10, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Kentucky Troopers, undated (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Lincoln, undated (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Mrs. Logan, undated (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Minty's Cavalry, undated (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Gen. Pope, undated (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - The Quaker Scout, undated (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Siege of Corinth, undated (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Townsend's Story, undated (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Tracy Tremmel, undated (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - USS Brooklyn, undated (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Vanquishing Vicksburg, undated (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Vicksburg, undated (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Misc. Titled Cartoons, undated (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Misc. Untitled Cartoons, undated (Box 10, Folder 61)
- Scrapbooks, 1858-1890s; MS2048 Series 3
  - Scrapbook 1858-69, 1858-1869 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    General note
    Selected items from this scrapbook are described below. Please note that this is not a comprehensive list of the materials within this scrapbook.
    - Examination, 02/11/1863-02/13/1863; Item 1
  - Scrapbook, 1875-1885 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1896-1898 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 1880s, 1880 ca. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Cartoon: Lincoln and soldiers, 1885 ca.; Item 1
      Text on reverse of cartoon: "T. T. #2 Reviewed by the President and Commander-in-Chief, Trib. 1 col"
  - Scrapbook 1890s, 1890 ca. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook: Cartoons, Washington Post, 1894-95, G. Y. Coffin, 1894-1895 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Cartoon: "The Men Who Fought, The Men Who Talk", 1895 ca.; Item 1
    - Cartoon: "Public hospital", 1895 ca.; Item 2
    - Cartoon: "Opening of the League Season 1895", Item 3
    - Cartoon: "Police Patrol", 1895 ca.; Item 4
- Diaries, 1859-1861; MS2048 Series 4
  - Diaries 1859-68, 1859-1868 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Loose Sketches and Photographs, undated; MS2048 Series 5
  - Youthful Sketches, 1858-1861 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Selected items from this folder are described below. Please note that this is not a comprehensive list of the materials within this folder.
    - Sketch: "Railroad cars", 1858 ca. --1861 ca.; Item 1
    - Sketch: "The Happy Family", 1858 ca. --1861 ca.; Item 2
  - Sketches, 1865 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sketches, 1865; Item 1
    - Sketches, 1866; Item 2
    - Sketches, 1868; Item 3
    - Sketches, 1869; Item 4
    - Sketches, 1870; Item 5
    - Sketches, 1872; Item 6
    - Sketches, 1873; Item 7
    - Sketches, 1874; Item 8
  - Sketches, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Sketches, undated; Item 1
    - Sketches, undated; Item 2
    - Sketches, undated; Item 3
  - Initial Letter Drawings, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Initial Letter Drawings, undated; Item 1
    - Initial Letter Drawings, undated; Item 2
    - Initial Letter Drawings, undated; Item 3
    - Initial Letter Drawings, undated; Item 4
    - Initial Letter Drawings, undated; Item 5
    - Initial Letter Drawings, undated; Item 6
    - Loose cartoons, undated; Item 7
  - Large Cartoons, 1885 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Photograph: George Yost Coffin, undated; Item 1
    Text on photograph: "George Y. Coffin"
  - Photograph: George Yost Coffin, undated; Item 2
  - Framed cartoon, 1870 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    [inscription on cartoon:] "A Strictly Authentic Portrait of the Eminent Artist G.Y. Coffin - May 8th 1870 - Ipse delineavit [drawn by himself]"